<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on Mainroad</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/categories/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on Mainroad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/categories/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Go Race Detector</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-03-09-golang-go-race-detector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-03-09-golang-go-race-detector/</guid>
      <description>Setting Up and Using the Go Race Detector The Go race detector is a powerful tool for identifying race conditions in concurrent Go programs. Race conditions occur when two or more goroutines access shared data concurrently, and at least one of the accesses is a write. This article will guide you through setting up the Go race detector and provide a sample race condition example.&#xA;Prerequisites Before you begin, ensure you have the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>context in Golang</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-05-golang-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-05-golang-context/</guid>
      <description>Q: What is context in Golang?&#xA;⭐ Answer:&#xA;In Go, the context package provides a way to control and manage the lifetime, deadlines, timeouts, and cancellation of goroutines, making it essential for handling long-running operations and request-scoped data.&#xA;Why is context needed? When working with concurrent operations like HTTP requests, database calls, or background tasks, we often need to:&#xA;Set timeouts to avoid indefinitely running processes. Propagate cancellations to prevent resource leaks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>pointers in Golang</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-05-golang-pointers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-05-golang-pointers/</guid>
      <description>Q: What are pointers in Go, and what are their uses?&#xA;⭐ Answer:&#xA;In Go, a pointer is a variable that stores the memory address of another variable, rather than the value itself. Pointers allow you to reference and manipulate variables indirectly, making them a powerful tool in Go programming.&#xA;How Pointers Work: When you declare a variable, the pointer holds the memory address of that variable, rather than the actual value.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rate Limiter in Golang</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-05-golang-rate-limiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-05-golang-rate-limiter/</guid>
      <description>Rate limiting in Go refers to the practice of controlling the rate at which certain actions or requests can be made over a given period of time. It is commonly used in networking, APIs, and services to ensure that resources are not overwhelmed by too many requests within a short time frame.&#xA;Rate limiting is essential for:&#xA;Preventing abuse (e.g., preventing DDoS attacks or excessive API calls) Ensuring fair usage of resources (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kafka Consumer Groups</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-04-kafka-consumer-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-02-04-kafka-consumer-groups/</guid>
      <description>The GroupID in Kafka is used to define a consumer group, which is a key concept in Kafka for managing how messages are consumed from topics. Here&amp;rsquo;s a detailed explanation of what GroupID: &amp;ldquo;fraud-detector&amp;rdquo; means in the context of below application code: package main import ( &amp;#34;context&amp;#34; &amp;#34;encoding/json&amp;#34; &amp;#34;log&amp;#34; &amp;#34;time&amp;#34; &amp;#34;github.com/segmentio/kafka-go&amp;#34; ) type Transaction struct { TransactionID string `json:&amp;#34;transaction_id&amp;#34;` UserID string `json:&amp;#34;user_id&amp;#34;` Amount float64 `json:&amp;#34;amount&amp;#34;` Location string `json:&amp;#34;location&amp;#34;` Timestamp string `json:&amp;#34;timestamp&amp;#34;` } func main() { // Initialize Kafka reader (consumer) reader := kafka.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Apache Kafka Core Concepts</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2025-01-25-kafka-core-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2025-01-25-kafka-core-concepts/</guid>
      <description>Apache Kafka Core Concepts Apache Kafka is a distributed streaming platform that is widely used for building real-time data pipelines and streaming applications. It is designed to handle high throughput, fault tolerance, and scalability. In this article, we will explore the core concepts of Kafka, along with some advanced topics, and provide examples in Golang to help you understand how to work with Kafka.&#xA;1. Topics A topic in Kafka is a category or feed name to which messages are sent by producers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Lang Unmarshall show errors</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2023-08-16-golang-unmarshall-show-errors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 13:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2023-08-16-golang-unmarshall-show-errors/</guid>
      <description>When you are Unmarshalling JSON in GO, you would probably get some error at some time regarding JSON format, fields or value types etc,.&#xA;So, most of us using simple syntax of the error to handle the error like in below example,&#xA;{: .light .w-75 .shadow .rounded-10 w=&amp;lsquo;1212&amp;rsquo; h=&amp;lsquo;668&amp;rsquo; }&#xA;package main import ( &amp;#34;encoding/json&amp;#34; &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; ) type A struct { Name string Email string } func main() { var a A bs := []byte(`{&amp;#34;Name&amp;#34;:&amp;#34;hello&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Email&amp;#34;:123}`) if e := json.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/hugo-template-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/hugo-template-primer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo uses the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/pkg/html/template/&#34;&gt;html/template&lt;/a&gt; library for&#xA;its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very&#xA;small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of&#xA;logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other&#xA;template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of&#xA;similarities in Go templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/getting-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/getting-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.&#xA;Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.&#xA;More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo&#xA;Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.&#xA;Follow the following steps:&#xA;Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313 Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedding Struct in Go</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2023-09-06-go-struct-embedding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2023-09-06-go-struct-embedding/</guid>
      <description>In Go, a struct is a composite data type that groups together variables (fields) under a single name. Structs are used to create custom data structures, similar to classes in other languages. You can also embed one struct within another struct to compose more complex data structures. This concept is known as &amp;ldquo;embedding&amp;rdquo; in Go.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of embedding in Go, along with its benefits, understanding, and conclusion:&#xA;Example of Embedding in Go: Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re building a system to manage different types of vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Books</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/post/2023-06-11-go-books-dariubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/post/2023-06-11-go-books-dariubs/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Go Books Books Starter Books Advanced Books Web Development Resources Books Starter Books The Little Go Book Free The Little Go Book is a free introduction to Google&amp;rsquo;s Go programming language. It&amp;rsquo;s aimed at developers who might not be quite comfortable with the idea of pointers and static typing. It&amp;rsquo;s longer than the other Little books, but hopefully still captures that little feeling.&#xA;An Introduction to Programming in Go Free This book is a short, concise introduction to computer programming using the language Go.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
